在上一集里
Previously on Transformers Prime...
钛师傅的讯息里还剩下四个加密坐标
Four sets of coordinates from Alpha Trion remain encrypted.
我们可以推断出那就是终极之钥的位置
It is logical to conclude that each corresponds to the location of one of the Omega keys.
糟了！
Scrap!
这个和擎天柱从我手中抢走的一模一样
It appears identical to the one taken from me by Optimus Prime.
或许 这只是拼图中的一块？
Pieces of a larger puzzle, perhaps.
钛师傅说过我们得把四个钥匙都弄到手
Alpha Trion said we need all four keys
才能让塞博特恩重生 记得吗？
to restore Cybertron, remember?
我们只要保护好手头上的
We just need to hang on to the one we have
再想法从威震天那里把剩下的抢过来就行了
find a way to get the others back from Megatron.
最后一个坐标也破解了
The final entry has been decoded.
坐标正在形成一幅图像
The coordinates are forming an image.
这是烟幕？！
Smokescreen?
擎天柱的新兵是最后一个铁堡遗物？
Prime's latest recruit is the final relic of Iacon!
不！
No!
太阳晒屁股啦！
Wakey, wakey.
啥？！
What?!
你在找相位仪么？谁找到归谁！
If you're looking for your Phase Shifter, finders keepers.
少耍嘴皮子 击倒！
Enough prattling, Knockout!
把最后一个铁堡遗物交出来 快！
Hand me the final Iacon relic... now.
唔…这我真的无能为力
Yeah, I can't really help you.
我只有一个相位仪
That's the only one I was packing.
声波
Soundwave.
你搞错了 威总
You got the wrong guy, chief.
擎天柱才是唯一能破译铁堡数据库的人
Optimus Prime's the one who can decode the Iacon database.
啊…可搞错的人是你
Ah, but you misunderstand.
最后一个数据已经被我们破解了！
The final entry has been decoded by us!
根据我们的发现
And according to our findings
显然我手上的人才是“真命天子”
it would appear I do indeed have the right guy.
问题在于你的身上到底还藏着什么
The question is, what is it that you are still packing?
哇哦 果然腹中有乾坤！
Why, hidden treasure, of course!
烟幕肯定是被带上霸天虎战舰了！
Smokescreen must have been taken aboard the Decepticon warship.
没法穿透战舰的屏障追踪他的信号
Tracing his signal through its shielding will be impossible.
继续监控所有频道 救护车
Continue monitoring all frequencies, Ratchet.
危在旦夕的不仅仅是烟幕的命运
Far more than Smokescreen's fate may be at stake.
我还是不明白 烟幕怎么会成为终极之钥？
I... don't get it. How could Smoke be an Omega key?
或许他并非钥匙本身 而是装载钥匙的容器？
Perhaps he isn't the key, but its container.
其他铁堡遗物是用宇宙舱送来的
The other Iacon relics were sent to Earth in pods.
为何独此与众不同？
Why not this one?
或许当霸天虎洗劫铁堡时
When the Decepticons stormed Iacon
钛师傅已来不及将最后一个钥匙送入太空了
it may have been too late for Alpha Trion
to launch the final Omega key into space...
…至少常规方法已经行不通了
at least, by standard means.
那么当烟幕昏迷时 他以为是被霸天虎打的
So Smokescreen assumed everything went black because he was hit by Decepticons.
但实际上那是钛师傅所为
But Alpha Trion's the one who actually turned out the kid's lights.
考虑到我的导师担心烟幕\N被敌人俘获而向他隐瞒事实
It stands to reason that my mentor did not want Smokescreen to know
…这事合情合理
what he was carrying in the event of capture.
既然遗物是活动的
And with a mobile relic
钛师傅自然无法提供确切的坐标
Alpha Trion couldn't possibly supply fixed coordinates.
于是钛大爷转而扔给我们一个线索 烟仔的大头照！
So the big "A" slipped us a clue instead... Smoke's mug shot.
但霸天虎抢先抓走了烟幕
But the Decepticons got to Smokescreen first.
恐怕他们也破解了同一个线索
I fear they have decoded the same clue.
又是一个一模一样的遗物？
Yet another of these identical relics?
快把它取出来！
Remove it swiftly.
乐意效劳
With pleasure.
人家一向讨厌比我还闪亮的漆面
I do so resent a finish flashier than my own.
哈 吓着你了吧！
Ha! Made you squirm.
梦幻般的效果…
Trippy.
…还可随意操控
And intuitive.
适当的接地功能 能防止使用者陷入地板
Proper grounding ensures that its user won't phase through the floor.
我让你快点！
I said swiftly.
啊 啊 把你的脏手拿开！
Ah. Ah. Get your stinkin' hand out of my gears!
嗯…这不是…拿到啦！
Mm, and... gotcha!
告诉我这些遗物作何用途！
Tell me the function of these relics.
门钩？刮胡刀？首饰？这可难住我了
Doorstops? Shavers? Bling? Beats me.
哼 可惜这小玩意儿不能让我探进他的大脑
Hmm. A pity this little gadget won't allow me to just reach into his brain pan and
把那些情报一把拽出来
pluck out the info.
幸运的是 我们拥有这样的设备
Fortunately, we possess a device that can.
尽管单个终极之钥毫无用处
Individually, each of these so-called Omega keys is useless.
但这仍能大大增加我的谈判筹码
Yet possessing even a single one grants me tremendous negotiating power
不管对方是汽车人还是霸天虎
with either Autobots or Decepticons.
不过 想像一下我成功得到其他三个的话…
Still, imagine if I manage to acquire the other three.
我可以让塞博特恩重生！\N并以“红蜘蛛一世”之名称帝…
I could revive Cybertron and seize the throne as Starscream the first.
至高无上的霸主！破坏大帝！
Supreme overlord and emperor of destruction!
可我不像威震天
But unlike Megatron
我没有建立这种强权统治的基础条件
I lack the necessary infrastructure to enforce such a reign.
没有战舰 没有军队 只有这破实验室里的东西
No warship, no army... only my meager laboratory finds
一个环陆桥的遥控开关 最后一剂红色能量液
a ground-bridge remote control, a single remaining dose of Red Energon
还有你 老朋友…
and you, old friend.
不过 我很乐意用这东西做笔交易
But I would all too gladly trade this
只为恢复以往的荣耀…
simply to be restored to my former glory.
我并未听说过这些终极之钥
While I am unfamiliar with the lore of these Omega keys
但钛师傅知道很多秘密
Alpha Trion knew many secrets
我们的先祖拥有许多神奇的科技
and the ancients possessed technology
在我们的现代科学中早已失传
that has long been lost to what we consider modern science.
尽管还不清楚功能和原理 但有一件事可以确定
Whatever their function, this much is certain.
那就是只有集齐四枚终极之钥 才能让塞博特恩复苏
We cannot restore Cybertron without all four Omega keys in our possession.
故乡的未来就指望它了！
The future of our home world depends on it.
观影结束
That's a wrap.
可以依我意愿…再造塞博特恩的力量…
The power to remake Cybertron as I see fit.
我会杀了擎天柱 夺回另外两枚钥匙
I will pry the other two keys from Optimus Prime's lifeless fingers.
我们必须找到汽车人基地的确切位置
We must find the exact location of the Autobot base.
必要的话 把烟幕的脑子撬开都行
Patch in and tear apart Smokescreen's mind, if you must.
由我来？
Me?
你说呢？
Who else?
你以为我会把护送钥匙的重任交付给你吗？
Do you think I would entrust you to see this key safely to the vault containing the other one?
呼…还是继续撬脑壳吧
Once more, into the brain pan.
不！别来了！别动我的脑袋！
No! Not again! Stay out of my head!
安分点儿 乱动只会让你的情况更糟
Now, now. You'll only make things worse for yourself.
更糟？怎么个糟法？
Worse how?
有一套啊 你这小滑头
Well, aren't you the clever one?
这艘船在万里高空之上 船上遍布霸天虎
This is ship is miles in the sky and swarming with Decepticons!
你真的以为自己可以逃脱？
Do you really think you can escape?
谁说我要逃了？
Who says I'm lookin' to escape?
灵机一动！
Think fast!
什么？！
What?!
出口不在这边儿？
Oh, this isn't the way out?
交出钥匙！
The keys.
可惜你不会飞
A pity you are incapable of flight.
切 好像我会怕似的？
Yeah, like I'm gonna let that stop me.
烟幕的信号又出现了！
Smokescreen's signal, it's back online!
这小子逃出了战舰！
The kid escaped the warship!
烟幕呼叫基地 我非常需要环陆桥！
Smokescreen to base. I could really use a ground bridge.
快去抢终极之钥 快！
Retrieve the Omega keys! Quickly!
会飞的！我需要会飞的！
Fliers! I need fliers!
设定坐标 怪了…
Setting coordinates. Strange.
有什么问题？
What's the problem?
烟幕的遥测数据不对劲
Smokescreen's telemetry data doesn't make sense.
我无法锁定他的位置！
I can't lock onto his position.
我发现问题所在了
I've isolated the problem.
烟幕正在自由落体！
Smokescreen is in free fall.
烟幕 我要在你的正下方开启环陆桥！
Smokescreen, I'm opening the ground bridge directly below you.
各位留神 我马上要进来了
Brace yourselves. I'm gonna make an entrance.
他…偏离路线了！
He's... off course.
你算偏了？
You missed?
再开一个 快！
Open another one... fast!
希望这接地功能 对实际地面不起作用！
I hope proper grounding on this thing doesn't apply to actual ground.
不！
No!
检查所有残骸！
Scour the wreckage!
把钥匙给老子找出来！
I want those keys!
嘿 救护车？
Hey, Ratchet.
我还是需要环陆桥！
I could still really use that ground bridge.
我早说了吧？
Did I tell you?
宿命！钛师傅知道我能保护好它！
Destiny! Alpha Trion knew I'd keep it safe.
干得不错 后生！
Nice work, kid.
威震天那儿就这一把钥匙
It was the only key in Megatron's vault.
那么现在有三枚钥匙了
Then three keys are accounted for.
第四枚仍在虎子战舰上的某处
Then the fourth is still somewhere on the Cons' warship.
除非…威震天一开始就没拿到那一个？
Unless... Megatron never had it to begin with?
高频信号
A high-frequency signal...
隐藏着一条信息
with an embedded message.
是红蜘蛛
Starscream.
我捡到了一个你们很想要的东西
"I have obtained something of interest to you
但似乎对我来说用处不大
which seems to be of no practical use to me".
肯定是终极之钥！
It's got to be the Omega key!
他就是打我闷棍的那混蛋！
He's the one who blindsided me!
除此之外别无可能
What else could Scream be referring to?
还有呢！带上医药箱
Ep, ep! There's more. "Bring medical kit.
作为交换 我只要求为我进行一次变形齿轮移植手术
I only ask for the surgical replacement of my T-Cog in return."
哈！说得好像我们会把他的翅膀还给他！
Heh! Like we're gonna give scream back his wings.
没有那把钥匙 塞博特恩将永无生机
Without the missing key, Cybertron will remain devoid of life.
我知道 这是破天荒的机会 但那可能是个圈套
Broken record, I know, but... it could be a trick.
红蜘蛛可能还不知道
It is possible that Starscream does not yet realize
所持之物的重大意义
the significance of what he holds.
而且我们也知道他很久不能飞了
And we do know that he's been incapable of flight for some time.
事关重大 我们必须考虑红蜘蛛的要求
The stakes are too great for us not to consider Starscream's proposal.
尽管如此 我们仍须小心戒备
However, we will take precautions.
在那儿！
There.
红蜘蛛？交出终极之钥
Starscream, show us the Omega key.
放弃吧 小红！
Give it up, Scream.
哈？
Huh?
太迟了
We're too late.
变形齿轮也帮不了他了
The T-Cog won't help him now.
看来这地儿现在由我做主
It would seem I have the run of the place.
哦…现在掏出你的心是多么容易啊！
Oh, how easy it would be to gut you.
干掉你们所有人！
To gut all of you.
可惜 本座另有要事…
But... first thing's first.
擎天柱把钥匙都放哪儿了？
Where does Optimus keep his key ring?
不在这儿 不在 不在
Not here. Nope. No.
我还在想那个婊子上哪儿去了呢
Bleh, I was wondering what happened to that wretch.
啊 这些人是不是以为我很闲！
Ah! Do they think I have all day?
啊 在这儿呐！
Ah, there you are.
奇怪 红蜘蛛死了有段时间了…
Curious. Starscream has been deceased for quite some time.
那怎么可能？他才刚给咱们发了消息啊
Well, how's that possible if he just sent us a message?
我们中计了！
We have been deceived.
喔哦 这是怎么了？
Whoa! Whoa! What was that?
阿尔茜 关掉环陆桥！
Arcee, close the ground bridge now.
现在我拿到了你们的小玩意儿
Now that I have your trinkets
我终于有空刮花你的…
I'm free to enjoy slitting your...
哼 可惜本座得赶时间…
But, as I appear to be pressed for time...
汽――车――人――
Autobots.
原――地――驻――守――
Maintain positions!
抱歉 你说什么？
I'm sorry. What was that?
呜哇哦哇…
Wo.. oh... woo... oh...
你们汽车人总以为自己多么优越
You Autobots think you're so superior
可实际上呢？
but do you know what you really are?
迟钝！
Slow!
红色能量耗尽了 是不？
The red energon wore off, didn't it?
他拿着终极之钥！
He has the Omega keys!
快点儿！
Come on!
不――！！！
No!!!
我们会抓住他的
We'll get them back.
钥匙对红蜘蛛一点用也没有
The keys can be of no use to Starscream
他不过是像吸屑虫一样见什么咬什么！
while he scrounges in the wild like some scraplet.
我们肯定能拿什么东西和他交换！
There must be something that we can offer him in exchange.
无论红蜘蛛有何企图
The fate of Cybertron now rests in Starscream's hands...
塞博特恩的命运都掌握在他手中了
Whatever his intention.
求您了 陛下
I beg you, my liege
请将我从这窘境中解脱出来吧！
release me from this absurd predicament!
不！你正好给那些胆敢让我失望之人
No! You shall serve as a constant reminder to those who dare
做个警示！
fail me.
我不能允许擎天柱成为塞博特恩的救世主！
I cannot allow Optimus Prime to be the one to revive Cybertron.
我们一定要找到汽车人基地 然后进攻 夺回终极之钥！
We will locate the Autobot base, invade it, and retrieve the Omega keys.
我已经去过了 且大功告成
Been there... done that.
请原谅我的不请自来 威震天陛下
Please pardon my unannounced visit, lord Megatron.
小人有礼物敬呈于您…
But I have come bearing a peace offering.